<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>bites | brews | paws</title>
<link>https://sinisterrob.github.io/book_review.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://sinisterrob.github.io/book_review.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>A personal take on Chicago food, music, photography, and other topics.</description>
<generator>quarto-1.4.550</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 06:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Galit (⭐)</title>
  <link>https://sinisterrob.github.io/food_review/2024-03-07-galit/2024-03-07-galit.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="menu" class="level1">
<h1>Menu</h1>
<p>We visited Galit, a Middle Eastern restaurant in the middle of the Lincoln Park neighborhood of Chicago last week.</p>
<p>Immediately upon sitting down, my first two thoughts were how busy the restaurant was, and how you could see directly into the busy kitchen. Since we had never been here, we ordered the “4-course choose your own adventure” and the wine accompaniment. To be honest, I have not tried many of these foods and spices before, so I wasn’t quite sure what anything was going to taste like.</p>
<p><img src="https://sinisterrob.github.io/img/galit-menu.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="hummus-salatim" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="hummus-salatim">Hummus &amp; Salatim</h2>
<p>To start things off, we had the masabacha hummus, labneh, sweet potato, ezme, and pickles.</p>
<p>My first thought when these plates came out were: “Wow, look at the size of that pita bread!” We were quite hungry since our reservations were for 8:45pm, so everything immediately looked very appetizing.</p>
<p>I was most interested in trying the sweet potato, the dish closest to me, so I tore a piece of the pita bread and ate it together with the sweet potato. It tasted fairly normal but tasty, and so did the pickles. I really like pickles and don’t get the opportunity enough to try pickled vegetables other than cucumbers.</p>
<p>The small dish with labneh was what I tried next, and with the pita it tasted kind of similar to butter on a roll but flavored a little more sweet and sour than butter.</p>
<p>Whitney liked the ezme on the far side of the table more than I did, but she loves tomato dishes more than me. It didn’t have a strong tomato flavor though and with the other spices it balanced out the other dishes pretty well.</p>
<p>Finally, we had the masabacha hummus in the middle which was delicious. I don’t normally eat hummus since I haven’t been sure if I liked it or not in the past, but this dish made me realize maybe I would like some types of hummus in my diet. Chickpeas are very nutritious and the consistency of the masabacha went perfectly with the remainder of my pita.</p>
<p><img src="https://sinisterrob.github.io/img/course-1.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The wine pairing for this meal was <a href="https://thesavorygrape.com/product/keush-ultra-blanc-de-noir-brut-nature/">Keush, ‘Ultra’ Blanc de Noir Brut Nature</a> from Armenia. I’m not really an expert when it comes to wine tasting so I can’t really comment too much on any of the specific flavors from the wines I had but this one was memorable for being light and bubbly, almost like a champagne.</p>
</section>
<section id="mezze" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="mezze">Mezze</h2>
<p>Next, for mezze (appetizers), we ordered the grape leaves and carrots.</p>
<p>My initial impression was that I really don’t know what either of these foods is going to taste like, but the grape leaves immediately looked more appetizing so I grabbed one, dipped it in the yellow saffron sauce and gave it a try.</p>
<p>To my palate, it was very bitter initially. It tasted very healthy and full of nutrients though, and although I don’t know what grape leaves taste like normally they seemed to me to be very fresh and authentic. I split the third one with Whitney after trying the carrots and that other half tasted much less bitter, especially after dipped in more of the saffron sauce.</p>
<p>The carrots had an overwhelming flavor, maybe the piece I initially got had a ton of duqqa, which has a variety of warm spices in it. That is definitely not a flavor that is common in American cuisine, so in the moment I was really struggling to come up with a term on how I could describe the flavor of the carrots. The spices were very aromatic, warm, and earthy. There was so much covering the carrots and the flavor was so strong that I had to leave some spices on the plate, but overall a very tasty pair of appetizers.</p>
<p><img src="https://sinisterrob.github.io/img/course-2.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The wine pairing for this meal was <a href="https://www.plummarket.com/store/2021-yarden-golan-heights-chardonnay-galilee.html">Yarden ‘Golan Heights’ Chardonnay Galilee</a> from Israel.</p>
</section>
<section id="over-coal" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="over-coal">Over Coal</h2>
<p>For our main course, I ordered the lamb basteeya and Whitney got the mushroom schnitzel. She just went vegetarian in January 2024 and this was the only vegetarian option on the menu, so we did not share these dishes with each other, other than when I tried one bite of the mushroom.</p>
<p>The lamb was delicious, I regret not trying more of the sauces on my plate but I was definitely feeling the effects of three glasses of wine after the waitress had brought us a glass of <a href="https://www.allstarwine.com/wines/Chateau-Musar-Gaston-Hochar-Chateau-Musar-Gaston-Hochar-2017-w4656143lr">Chateau Musar Gaston Hochar</a> from Lebanon to enjoy with our entree.</p>
<p><img src="https://sinisterrob.github.io/img/course-3.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The lamb was tender and tasty, and it kind of reminded me of a pot pie, except sweeter. The powdered sugar (at least that’s what I think it was - it was very sweet) topping was a break from the slight bitterness of the carrots and grape leaves of the previous meal. I tried a bite of the mushroom schnitzel. The outer coating of those was fried to a nice and crispy consistency, although the mushroom was a little more sour than I was expecting.</p>
<p>I know that Lion’s Mane mushroom is supposed to be a natural mushroom good for boosting memory though. I’ve only ever really tried it through supplements. There’s a really cool coffee shop in the West Loop called <a href="https://sawadacoffee.com/">Sawada Coffee</a> that gives you the option to add Lion’s Mane mushroom powder to your coffee and it’s delicious - maybe that will be the next review. Stay tuned!</p>
</section>
<section id="dessert" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="dessert">Dessert</h2>
<p>For our dessert, we got the olive oil cake. I wanted to try the phyllo pie - maybe next time! The crispy meringue was interesting, obviously very light and like biting into a cloud. The cake was definitely sweeter than I was expecting, I don’t know why I expected a much stronger flavor of olive oil.</p>
<p><img src="https://sinisterrob.github.io/img/course-4.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The final wine pairing was a special one, it was a wine that has been brewed in the same method since biblical times which involves adding new barrels of wine to older barrels that are never fully emptied. The result was a very sweet and deliciously aged dessert wine called <a href="https://taylorswineshop.com/products/keo-st-john-commandaria">Keo St.&nbsp;John Commandaria</a> from Cypress that was very enjoyable to drink when paired with the olive oil cake.</p>
<p><img src="https://sinisterrob.github.io/img/biblical-wine.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="rating" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="rating">Rating</h2>
<p><strong>Overall score:</strong> 4.6 out of 5.0 stars</p>
<p>Would definitely go back here if I ever have the opportunity!</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://sinisterrob.github.io/food_review/2024-03-07-galit/2024-03-07-galit.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://sinisterrob.github.io/../../img/course-1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>About</title>
  <link>https://sinisterrob.github.io/about.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This site was made using a <a href="https://quarto.org/docs/websites/">Quarto website</a> and published for free using <a href="https://quarto.org/docs/publishing/github-pages.html">Github Pages</a>.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://sinisterrob.github.io/about.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:30:19 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>About Me</title>
  <link>https://sinisterrob.github.io/about_me.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 
<p>I’m Robert, an actuarial consultant living in Chicago. I like photography, eating and reviewing good food, travelling, biking, chess, predictive modelling, data visualization, watching Texas Longhorns football, and chilling with my cats. I’m planning on using this blog to write about those things and more, so stay tuned!</p>


 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://sinisterrob.github.io/about_me.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:30:19 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chess Analysis</title>
  <link>https://sinisterrob.github.io/chess_analysis.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Reserving this page for when I want to do some analysis of my own chess games. One of my goals for 2024 is to try to get an official chess rating.</p>
<iframe src="https://lichess.org/embed/game/lhPpPjFv?theme=blue&amp;bg=light" width="600" height="397" frameborder="0"></iframe>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://sinisterrob.github.io/chess_analysis.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:30:19 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Food Reviews</title>
  <link>https://sinisterrob.github.io/food_review.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>On this page I will review restaurants and talk about the wide variety of food that is available in Chicago (and occasionally other cities!)</p>




<div class="quarto-listing quarto-listing-container-grid" id="listing-listing">
<div class="list grid quarto-listing-cols-3">
<div class="g-col-1" data-index="0" data-listing-date-sort="1709791200000" data-listing-file-modified-sort="1709943376837" data-listing-date-modified-sort="NaN" data-listing-reading-time-sort="6" data-listing-word-count-sort="1014">
<a href="./food_review/2024-03-07-galit/2024-03-07-galit.html" class="quarto-grid-link">
<div class="quarto-grid-item card h-100 card-left">
<p class="card-img-top">
<img src="https://sinisterrob.github.io/../../img/course-1.jpg" class="thumbnail-image card-img" style="height: 150px;">
</p>
<div class="card-body post-contents">
<h5 class="no-anchor card-title listing-title">
Galit (⭐)
</h5>
<div class="card-text listing-description">
I ventured out to the Michelin Star restaurant named Galit in Lincoln Park to give chef Zach Engel’s take on Middle-Eastern cuisine a try.
</div>
<div class="card-attribution card-text-small justify">
<div class="listing-author">

</div>
<div class="listing-date">
Mar 7, 2024
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</a>
</div>
</div>
<div class="listing-no-matching d-none">
No matching items
</div>
</div> ]]></description>
  <guid>https://sinisterrob.github.io/food_review.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:30:19 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://sinisterrob.github.io/img/biblical-wine.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Music Reviews</title>
  <link>https://sinisterrob.github.io/music_review.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Reserving this page for when I want to do some music reviews.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://sinisterrob.github.io/music_review.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:30:19 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Personal Blog</title>
  <link>https://sinisterrob.github.io/personal_blog.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>On this page I will talk about random personal topics that are interesting to me.</p>




<div class="quarto-listing quarto-listing-container-grid" id="listing-listing">
<div class="list grid quarto-listing-cols-3">

</div>
<div class="listing-no-matching d-none">
No matching items
</div>
</div> ]]></description>
  <guid>https://sinisterrob.github.io/personal_blog.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:30:19 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Photography</title>
  <link>https://sinisterrob.github.io/photography.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://lightroom.adobe.com/shares/2286a1c21a514e5c9506d3b4854d02cb">Two Weeks in Vietnam</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://lightroom.adobe.com/shares/0c2103ef215a4861a3e84d57c1af5e88">Kedzie Wells L Train S Curve</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://lightroom.adobe.com/shares/26fa2a3a86234bafa68bbdf39d28ae82">Flowers of Đà Lạt</a></p></li>
</ul>
<div>

</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-panel" data-layout-ncol="2">
<div class="quarto-layout-row">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><a href="data/quincy.jpg" class="lightbox" data-gallery="quarto-lightbox-gallery-1" data-glightbox="description: .lightbox-desc-1" title="Quincy"><img src="https://sinisterrob.github.io/data/quincy.jpg" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" alt="Quincy"></a></p>
<figcaption>Quincy</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: flex-start;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><a href="data/enyo.jpg" class="lightbox" data-gallery="quarto-lightbox-gallery-2" data-glightbox="description: .lightbox-desc-2" title="Enyo"><img src="https://sinisterrob.github.io/data/enyo.jpg" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" alt="Enyo"></a></p>
<figcaption>Enyo</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>




 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://sinisterrob.github.io/photography.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:30:19 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://sinisterrob.github.io/data/quincy.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Professional Blog</title>
  <link>https://sinisterrob.github.io/professional_blog.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>On this page I will talk about random professional topics that are interesting to me.</p>




<div class="quarto-listing quarto-listing-container-grid" id="listing-listing">
<div class="list grid quarto-listing-cols-3">

</div>
<div class="listing-no-matching d-none">
No matching items
</div>
</div> ]]></description>
  <guid>https://sinisterrob.github.io/professional_blog.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:30:19 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Robert’s Github Site</title>
  <link>https://sinisterrob.github.io/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This is a Quarto website hosted for free on a <a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Page</a>.</p>
<p>To learn more about Quarto websites visit <a href="https://quarto.org/docs/websites" class="uri">https://quarto.org/docs/websites</a>.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://sinisterrob.github.io/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:30:19 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://sinisterrob.github.io/img/bites_brews_paws.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="86" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
