<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>bites | brews | paws</title>
<link>https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/food_review.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/food_review.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>A personal take on Chicago food, music, photography, and other topics.</description>
<image>
<url>https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/img/biblical-wine.jpg</url>
<title>bites | brews | paws</title>
<link>https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/food_review.html</link>
</image>
<generator>quarto-1.4.550</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 06:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Sawada Coffee</title>
  <link>https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/food_review/2024-03-09-sawada-coffee/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="menu" class="level1">
<h1>Menu</h1>
<p>Sawada Coffee is an busy and trendy coffee shop in the West Loop neighborhood.</p>
<p>They have a small menu, but the drinks (Military Latte, Black Camo Latte, High Five Mocha) are immediately enticing once you step inside and see the cozy shop interior for yourself.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/img/sawada-menu.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="trendy-curated" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="trendy-curated">Trendy &amp; Curated</h2>
<p>First thing to mention in my review - this place is extremely popular and with good reason.</p>
<p>It’s in the busy West Loop area, and while other restaurants are more open and visible especially on a weekend, this cafe is more of a tucked-away gem.</p>
<p>Once you step inside the front door, you are greeted by a waiting area with plenty of graffiti and stickers on the walls and a dimly lit chandelier.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/img/chandelier.jpg" class="img-fluid"> All three of the times I’ve been here, the line was nearly out the door, but fortunately it moves efficiently.</p>
<p>Once you move up a few places in line you see it’s a trendy and artsy coffee bar with some unique drink options, and the drinks and decor definitely reflect that.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/img/skateboard.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The shop is owned by world-renowed (or at least coffee world-renowned…) Hiroshi Sawada, and in 2015 it received recognition as one of the “Best Coffee Shops in Chicago” as well as one of “10 Cool Indie Coffee Shops from Coast to Coast”.</p>
<p>My favorite part would have to be the string lights hanging from the ceiling, large tables that almost seem to encourage you to strike up a morning conversation with other customers, and a large sunken dining area with a Texas style BBQ restaurant providing delicious food.</p>
<p>When visiting, it was also so busy that it it was hard to take pictures of the decor without also taking pictures of other customers, which I don’t normally like to do. So honestly, I didn’t worry about taking too many pictures and instead enjoyed the experience. The overall vibe is something that’s best experienced by visiting!</p>
</section>
<section id="high-five-mocha-a-cookie" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="high-five-mocha-a-cookie">High Five Mocha &amp; a cookie!</h2>
<p>The High Five Mocha is a unique and specialty drink. It’s inspired by their sister restaurant, <a href="https://www.highfiveramen.com/">High Five Ramen</a>. Maybe I should do a review of this place in the future?</p>
<p>Mocha is definitely my go-to coffee, and I remember the first time I tried the High Five it tasted nothing like a normal mocha. The first flavor note is actually orange peel, and it comes across <strong>really</strong> strong.</p>
<p>That’s because it has sanshō and orange peel added. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zanthoxylum_piperitum">Sanshō</a> is an intense, aromatic, high toned Japanese spice. I couldn’t tell you exactly what that tastes like because the High Five Mocha tastes strongly like orange, chocolate, and coffee to me, but I’m sure if I get the chance to try an isolated sample of sanshō in the future it would probably be distinct and recognizable.</p>
<p>Either way, I drank my coffee way too quickly - 30 seconds flat - and tried a bite of the chocolate cookie.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/img/mocha-cookie.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The cookie was delicious, of course. I don’t know that I can honestly give a thorough review of a cookie, because it’s just chocolate and powdered sugar. All I can say about it was it was extremely sweet and too much to finish in one serving especially since I had just eaten lunch.</p>
<p>I was also inspired from my <a href="../../food_review/2024-03-07-galit/index.html">Galit Review</a> to get Lion’s Mane mushroom added to my coffee for an extra $3. Normally I get CBD in my coffee whenever it’s an option, but I’ve always heard of Lion’s Mane being a nootropic that supposedly <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC10675414/">boosts cognitive performance and memory</a>. I’m not sure if I 100% believe all of the claimed effects, but I do know that mushrooms are healthy for you anyway, so maybe I’ll see some marginal effects!</p>
</section>
<section id="rating" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="rating">Rating</h2>
<p><strong>Overall score:</strong> 4.4 out of 5.0 stars</p>
<p>Overall, Sawada Coffee is an amazing coffee shop that gets pretty crowded during peak hours. The inside of the cafe is beautiful, you could really spend all day studying here and having pretty unique coffee flavors that you can’t find anywhere else. I love that you can put CBD or Lion’s Mane in your drink for a reasonable charge (although the coffee is specialty and the price reflects that.) And although I didn’t eat it on this visit, the Texas style BBQ served by Green Street is delicious.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/food_review/2024-03-09-sawada-coffee/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/../../img/mocha-cookie.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Galit (⭐)</title>
  <link>https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/food_review/2024-03-07-galit/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="menu" class="level1">
<h1>Menu</h1>
<p>We visited Galit, a Middle Eastern restaurant in the middle of the Lincoln Park neighborhood of Chicago last week.</p>
<p>Immediately upon sitting down, my first two thoughts were how busy the restaurant was, and how you could see directly into the busy kitchen. Since we had never been here, we ordered the “4-course choose your own adventure” and the wine accompaniment. To be honest, I have not tried many of these foods and spices before, so I wasn’t quite sure what anything was going to taste like.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/img/galit-menu.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="hummus-salatim" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="hummus-salatim">Hummus &amp; Salatim</h2>
<p>To start things off, we had the masabacha hummus, labneh, sweet potato, ezme, and pickles.</p>
<p>My first thought when these plates came out were: “Wow, look at the size of that pita bread!” We were quite hungry since our reservations were for 8:45pm, so everything immediately looked very appetizing.</p>
<p>I was most interested in trying the sweet potato, the dish closest to me, so I tore a piece of the pita bread and ate it together with the sweet potato. It tasted fairly normal but tasty, and so did the pickles. I really like pickles and don’t get the opportunity enough to try pickled vegetables other than cucumbers.</p>
<p>The small dish with labneh was what I tried next, and with the pita it tasted kind of similar to butter on a roll but flavored a little more sweet and sour than butter.</p>
<p>Whitney liked the ezme on the far side of the table more than I did, but she loves tomato dishes more than me. It didn’t have a strong tomato flavor though and with the other spices it balanced out the other dishes pretty well.</p>
<p>Finally, we had the masabacha hummus in the middle which was delicious. I don’t normally eat hummus since I haven’t been sure if I liked it or not in the past, but this dish made me realize maybe I would like some types of hummus in my diet. Chickpeas are very nutritious and the consistency of the masabacha went perfectly with the remainder of my pita.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/img/course-1.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The wine pairing for this meal was <a href="https://thesavorygrape.com/product/keush-ultra-blanc-de-noir-brut-nature/">Keush, ‘Ultra’ Blanc de Noir Brut Nature</a> from Armenia. I’m not really an expert when it comes to wine tasting so I can’t really comment too much on any of the specific flavors from the wines I had but this one was memorable for being light and bubbly, almost like a champagne.</p>
</section>
<section id="mezze" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="mezze">Mezze</h2>
<p>Next, for mezze (appetizers), we ordered the grape leaves and carrots.</p>
<p>My initial impression was that I really don’t know what either of these foods is going to taste like, but the grape leaves immediately looked more appetizing so I grabbed one, dipped it in the yellow saffron sauce and gave it a try.</p>
<p>To my palate, it was very bitter initially. It tasted very healthy and full of nutrients though, and although I don’t know what grape leaves taste like normally they seemed to me to be very fresh and authentic. I split the third one with Whitney after trying the carrots and that other half tasted much less bitter, especially after dipped in more of the saffron sauce.</p>
<p>The carrots had an overwhelming flavor, maybe the piece I initially got had a ton of duqqa, which has a variety of warm spices in it. That is definitely not a flavor that is common in American cuisine, so in the moment I was really struggling to come up with a term on how I could describe the flavor of the carrots. The spices were very aromatic, warm, and earthy. There was so much covering the carrots and the flavor was so strong that I had to leave some spices on the plate, but overall a very tasty pair of appetizers.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/img/course-2.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The wine pairing for this meal was <a href="https://www.plummarket.com/store/2021-yarden-golan-heights-chardonnay-galilee.html">Yarden ‘Golan Heights’ Chardonnay Galilee</a> from Israel.</p>
</section>
<section id="over-coal" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="over-coal">Over Coal</h2>
<p>For our main course, I ordered the lamb basteeya and Whitney got the mushroom schnitzel. She just went vegetarian in January 2024 and this was the only vegetarian option on the menu, so we did not share these dishes with each other, other than when I tried one bite of the mushroom.</p>
<p>The lamb was delicious, I regret not trying more of the sauces on my plate but I was definitely feeling the effects of three glasses of wine after the waitress had brought us a glass of <a href="https://www.allstarwine.com/wines/Chateau-Musar-Gaston-Hochar-Chateau-Musar-Gaston-Hochar-2017-w4656143lr">Chateau Musar Gaston Hochar</a> from Lebanon to enjoy with our entree.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/img/course-3.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The lamb was tender and tasty, and it kind of reminded me of a pot pie, except sweeter. The powdered sugar (at least that’s what I think it was - it was very sweet) topping was a break from the slight bitterness of the carrots and grape leaves of the previous meal. I tried a bite of the mushroom schnitzel. The outer coating of those was fried to a nice and crispy consistency, although the mushroom was a little more sour than I was expecting.</p>
<p>I know that Lion’s Mane mushroom is supposed to be a natural mushroom good for boosting memory though. I’ve only ever really tried it through supplements. There’s a really cool coffee shop in the West Loop called <a href="https://sawadacoffee.com/">Sawada Coffee</a> that gives you the option to add Lion’s Mane mushroom powder to your coffee and it’s delicious - maybe that will be the next review. Stay tuned!</p>
</section>
<section id="dessert" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="dessert">Dessert</h2>
<p>For our dessert, we got the olive oil cake. I wanted to try the phyllo pie - maybe next time! The crispy meringue was interesting, obviously very light and like biting into a cloud. The cake was definitely sweeter than I was expecting, I don’t know why I expected a much stronger flavor of olive oil.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/img/course-4.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The final wine pairing was a special one, it was a wine that has been brewed in the same method since biblical times which involves adding new barrels of wine to older barrels that are never fully emptied. The result was a very sweet and deliciously aged dessert wine called <a href="https://taylorswineshop.com/products/keo-st-john-commandaria">Keo St.&nbsp;John Commandaria</a> from Cypress that was very enjoyable to drink when paired with the olive oil cake.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/img/biblical-wine.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="rating" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="rating">Rating</h2>
<p><strong>Overall score:</strong> 4.6 out of 5.0 stars</p>
<p>Would definitely go back here if I ever have the opportunity! Thanks for reading, and shalom y’all!</p>
<p><img src="https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/img/shalom.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/food_review/2024-03-07-galit/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://www.bitesbrewspaws.com/../../img/course-1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
